<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Online Learning | </title>
    <link>https://tao-l.github.io/tags/online-learning/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://tao-l.github.io/tags/online-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Online Learning</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://tao-l.github.io/media/icon_hu7729264130191091259.png</url>
      <title>Online Learning</title>
      <link>https://tao-l.github.io/tags/online-learning/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning a Game by Paying the Agents</title>
      <link>https://tao-l.github.io/pub_conference/zhang-learning-2026/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tao-l.github.io/pub_conference/zhang-learning-2026/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning to Play Multi-Follower Bayesian Stackelberg Games</title>
      <link>https://tao-l.github.io/pub_conference/personnat-learning-2026/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tao-l.github.io/pub_conference/personnat-learning-2026/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generalized Principal-Agent Problem with a Learning Agent</title>
      <link>https://tao-l.github.io/pub_journal/lin-generalized-2026/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tao-l.github.io/pub_journal/lin-generalized-2026/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Please see the &lt;a href=&#34;https://tao-l.github.io/publication/lin-generalized-2025&#34;&gt;conference version&lt;/a&gt; of this work for details.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the Coordination of Value-Maximizing Bidders</title>
      <link>https://tao-l.github.io/working_papers/guan-coordination-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tao-l.github.io/working_papers/guan-coordination-2025/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generalized Principal-Agent Problem with a Learning Agent</title>
      <link>https://tao-l.github.io/pub_conference/lin-generalized-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tao-l.github.io/pub_conference/lin-generalized-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Classic principal-agent problems such as Stackelberg games, contract design, and Bayesian persuasion, often assume that the agent is able to best respond to the principal&amp;rsquo;s committed strategy.
We study repeated generalized principal-agent problems under the assumption that the principal does not have commitment power and the agent uses algorithms to learn to respond to the principal. We reduce this problem to a one-shot generalized principal-agent problem where the agent approximately best responds. Using this reduction, we show that: (1) If the agent uses contextual no-regret learning algorithms with regret $\mathrm{Reg}(T)$, then the principal can guarantee utility at least $U^* - \Theta\big(\sqrt{\tfrac{\mathrm{Reg}(T)}{T}}\big)$, where $U^*$ is the principal&amp;rsquo;s optimal utility in the classic model with a best-responding agent.
(2) If the agent uses contextual no-swap-regret learning algorithms with swap-regret $\mathrm{SReg}(T)$, then the principal cannot obtain utility more than $U^* + O(\frac{\mathrm{SReg(T)}}{T})$.
But (3) if the agent uses mean-based learning algorithms (which can be no-regret but not no-swap-regret), then the principal can sometimes do significantly better than $U^*$.
These results not only refine previous results in Stackelberg games and contract design, but also lead to new results for Bayesian persuasion with a learning agent and all generalized principal-agent problems where the agent does not have private information.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning Thresholds with Latent Values and Censored Feedback</title>
      <link>https://tao-l.github.io/pub_conference/zhang-learning-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tao-l.github.io/pub_conference/zhang-learning-2024/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nash Convergence of Mean-Based Learning Algorithms in First Price Auctions</title>
      <link>https://tao-l.github.io/pub_conference/deng-nash-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tao-l.github.io/pub_conference/deng-nash-2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The convergence properties of learning dynamics in repeated auctions is a timely and important question, with numerous applications in, e.g., online advertising markets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work focuses on repeated first-price auctions where bidders with fixed values learn to bid using mean-based algorithms &amp;mdash; a large class of online learning algorithms that include popular no-regret algorithms such as Multiplicative Weights Update and Follow the Perturbed Leader. We completely characterize the learning dynamics of mean-based algorithms, under two notions of convergence: &lt;strong&gt;(1) time-average:&lt;/strong&gt; the fraction of rounds where bidders play a Nash equilibrium converges to 1; &lt;strong&gt;(2) last-iterate:&lt;/strong&gt; the mixed strategy profile of bidders converges to a Nash equilibrium. Specifically, the results depend on the number of bidders with the highest value:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If the number is at least three, the dynamics almost surely converges to a Nash equilibrium of the auction, in both time-average and last-iterate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If the number is two, the dynamics almost surely converges to a Nash equilibrium in time-average but not necessarily last-iterate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If the number is one, the dynamics may not converge to a Nash equilibrium in time-average or last-iterate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our discovery opens up new possibilities in the study of the convergence of learning dynamics.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
